Subindex build by Linnet
孩子们，在2011年十月 你们的Robin阿姨在接受心理治疗
NARRATOR: Kids, in October 2011, your Aunt Robin was in therapy.
让人意想不到的是 一切进展良好
And against all logic, it was actually going well.
为什么？
But why?
为什么我总要给自己找不开心的理由？
Why-why am I constantly looking for reasons not to be happy?
也许是最终开心起来这个想法
Maybe because the idea of finally being happy...
把你吓到了
terrifies you.
我去，全被你说中了
Bro, you are killing it today.
Pshh!
我们今天状态不错
We got something good here.
我们要征服我对快乐的恐惧!
We are totes gonna conquer my fear of abandonment!
恐怕我们不能再见了
I can't see you anymore.
不错
(laughs) Nice.
"Oh,不！你再也不理我了！"
"Oh, no! You're abandoning me!"
Oh,不！你再也不理我了?
Oh, no. You're abandoning me?
对不起，我要搬到阿拉斯加了
I'm sorry. I'm moving to Alaska.
故事就此也许该结束了
NARRATOR: And that might have been the end of it.
但一周后...
But a week later...
Kevin?!
你怎么来这里了？
What are you doing here?
好吧，我对你撒谎了， 我没有搬到阿拉斯加去
Okay, look, I lied to you about moving to Alaska.
但我的确不能再见你了。
I-I had to stop seeing you.
为什么？
Why?
因为我觉得你太可爱了
'Cause I think you're cute.
所以从职业伦理上来说， 假如我对你有感觉的话
And ethically, I can't be your therapist
我就不能当你的心理治疗师了
if I'm attracted to you.
噢，我懂了， 你不把我当作病人
Oh, I get it. You dump me as a patient
是因为要约我出来？
just so you can ask me out?
不，我不会约你出来。
I'm not gonna ask you out.
你不会么？
You're not?
不，我们是在心理治疗时认识的。
No. We met in therapy.
跟病人约会是不合适的。
It's inappropriate for me to date a patient.
不论如何，见到你很高兴。
Anyway, it was nice seeing you.
Hey, 等等
Hey, wait.
你是怎么定义"约会"的？
How do you define "date"?
两个人在一起吃饭
Two people having a meal together,
面对面的坐着
sitting across the table
四目相对
making googly eyes at each other...
那么，两个人并肩坐 各自吃饭
What about two people eating alone, sitting side by side,
跟服务生四目相对 怎么样？
making googly eyes at the coffee maker?
好吧，那么就不是约会
Okay, it's not a date.
是的，不是约会
Exactly. Not a date.
从此Robin和Kevin  在那个星期的每一天
NARRATOR: And so Robin and Kevin had breakfast alone,
都肩并着肩 各自吃早饭
side by side every day that week.
直到有一天...
Until finally...
Oh, hey!
对不起，没出租车了
Sorry. No cabs.
跑了40个街区 才到这里
Ran 40 blocks all the way here.
也许路上撞到了个老太太
May have knocked an old lady
但我不确定 我没回头
into the street, don't know, I didn't look back.
我们还是去约会吧！
Let's just go on a real date.
好主意
Yeah, that might be a good idea.
总算成了！
Finally!
How I Met Your Mother 7x05  Field Trip
? How I Met Your Mother 7x05 ? Field Trip Original Air Date on October 10, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman == == 翻译 by 猪叔是坏蛋 == == 同步 by 我恨猪叔 ==
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
== 制作 by 猪叔欠我一顿饭 == == 吐槽 by 猪叔下次来接我 == == 打字 by 猪叔希腊语加油 ==
?
我等不及要去看电影了
Oh, I can't wait to see that movie.
电影好看么？
Is it good?
棒极了 等等 假设一下
Awesome. Wait, totally hypothetically,
假如电影情节纠结波折
do you like movies with a shocking twist where all
最后主角死光光， 你喜不喜欢?
the main characters die at the end?
喜欢
Yes.
你会爱死这电影的！
You will love this movie.
Hey, 大家
Hey, guys.
Hey, Marshall. 肿么了
Hey, Marshall. What's up?
我来讲讲发生了神马
Well, I'll tell you what's up.
你们说听过我的老板 Garrison Cootes,是
You know how my boss, Garrison Cootes, is,
世界上最著名的
like, the most famous environmental lawyer
环保律师吧？
in the world?
yeah...
ALL: Yeah...
我的意思是说， 是他还是另外的一个人
I mean, it's him or the other guy.
Anthony Howel爵士?
Sir Anthony Howel?
yeah...
ALL: Yeah...
不管如何，他都是个很重要的人
Anyway, he's an important guy, okay?
今天工作的时候
And so today at work,
我试着向他表现出我强硬的一面
I was trying to show him that I'm tough.
我一直在想这事...
I've been thinking about this
假如我们跟Gruber Pharmaceuticals
settlement offer we're about
的和解协议
to get from Gruber Pharmaceuticals.
如果少于两千万美元的话
If it's anything less than $20 million,
我要抓住那些
then I'm gonna grab
玷污地球 家园的人的...
those corporate Earth rapists by their...
等等，我要说明一下
Okay, I'm just gonna say something.
我的肚子里面正怀着孩子
I'm growing a child in my belly,
这个孩子现在正在长耳朵
a child that just developed ears.
这是一件十分薄的毛衣
This is a very thin sweater.
所以你要讲些什么的话...
So please, if you must tell your story...
请讲一些和善点的话...
just make it cheerful.
和善的话
Cheerful.
OK
Okay...
我要抓住那些公司的
Then I'm gonna grab those corporate...
员工...
employees...
的汗流浃背的颤抖的...
by their sweaty, dangling...
双手...
hands...
挤得这些贪婪的...
and squeeze until those greedy sons of...
人们...认识到 我是地球母亲的...
parents... realize that I'm the baddest mother...
捍卫者
nature lover around.
我感觉这简直是在 CCTV6上看色戒
It's like watching The Breakfast Club on TBS.
那么他说了什么？
So what did he say?
Marshall, 弯下腰 让我能把手放到你肩上
Marshall, bend down so I can put my arm around you.
嗯，很好
That's all the way down. That's good.
Gruber Pharmaceuticals 是一家由
Gruber Pharmaceuticals is a company full
一群忠于职守的好心人组成的公司
of well-meaning people doing their jobs,
就跟你我一样
just like you and me.
弟兄们，我怕Garrison Cootes 变得软弱了
Guys, I'm afraid that Garrison Cootes has gone soft!
他就跟泰迪熊一样！
He's like a teddy bear!
一个泰迪熊还是 一只伊渥克? （一种星球大战的动物，跟泰迪熊长的很像）
A teddy bear or an Ewok?
平时看起来 既萌又可爱的样子
You know, cute and cuddly around the village,
但是当星级战争一旦开始...
but once the battle starts...
他会用巨大的原木 来把你的金属头骨给敲碎
He'll smash in your metal skull with giant swinging logs.
Marshall!
好吧，他会拥抱你
Okay, he'll hug you
直到你平和的同意 关闭死星
until you agree to peaceably shut down the Death Star.
Hi,亲爱的
NORA: Hi, sweetie.
Hey.
你们在谈什么呢？
What are we all talking about?
伊渥克
Ewoks.
Ugh, 我讨厌伊渥克
Ugh, I hate the Ewoks.
知道有关伊渥克在电影里 最好场面是什么么？
The only good thing about Ewoks in that movie?
就是看他们死掉的场面
You got to see some of them die.
Well,我想来一杯
Well, I fancy a pint.
Nora讨厌伊渥克
Nora hates Ewoks.
Well,我要跟她分手
Well, I have to break up with her.
当你们跟她说 这个消息的时候温柔点
Be gentle when you tell her, guys.
我会在韦加斯给们打电话 记得跟我说当时的情况
I'll call you from Vegas. Tell me how it went. Okay.
Okay, Barney!
坐下！
Sit down!
不喜欢伊渥克
Not liking Ewoks
不是你要跟 某人分手的原因
is no reason not to date somebody.
是啊，你看，谁知道恋爱里面的各种规矩？
Yeah, I mean, who knows what the rules are, ya know?
你看，你在跟一个 不喜欢伊渥克的女孩子约会
I mean, you're dating a girl who doesn't like Ewoks,
我在跟我的前心理治疗师约会
I'm dating my former therapist.
- Oh! - Eww!
全球有上千万观众每周都看我们吐槽呢！
We are gentlemen of Harvard!
这没什么！
It's not a big deal!
Robin, 如果你问一百个人,
Robin, if you asked a hundred people,
"天底下最不该跟谁约会?"
"Who's the worst person you could possibly date?"
九十九个人都会说 "你的心理治疗师"
they'd all say, "Your therapist."
只有一个会说 "Barney."
Except the ones saying "Barney."
Hey! 好吧，有道理
Hey! Yeah, that tracks.
Well,我要早点走了
Well, I should get going.
我明天要去进行场实地教学
I got the big field trip tomorrow.
实地教学？
Field trip?
对我要带我的
Yeah. I'm taking
建筑学导论班
my Intro to Architecture class
去GNB大厦的建筑工地
to the GNB Tower construction site.
我要让他们对
I'm trying to get them interested
称为一名建筑师产生兴趣
in architecture as a career.
为什么？我们 缺建筑了？
Why? Are we running out of buildings?
我们缺无聊的人了？
Are we running out of boring people?
这是件大事，好不？
Guys, this is a big deal, okay?
要是我能让一个孩子对 建筑产生兴趣
If I can get just one kid interested in
成为一名建筑师...
becoming an architect...
OK，你最好就此打住
Okay, I'm just gonna stop you right there.
Ted, 这是一门导论课
Ted, it's an Intro class.
不要在导论课上摆一副
Yeah, don't try to Stand and Deliver
为人师表的样子
an Intro class.
除非这课让你不会再宿醉
Nobody takes an Intro class to get on any other path
否则没人会对 一门导论课有太多兴趣
but the path to not being hungover anymore.
我这知识是从 常识导论 上学来的
I learned that in my Intro to something-ology class.
能在常识导论课上学到这个很好
Well that's fine for something-ology,
但是明早九点整
but tomorrow at 9:00 a.m. sharp
建筑学导论依旧还是要去现场教学
Intro to Architecture is going on a field trip!
一共有200个学生
All 200 of 'em.
现在是9:45.
Well, it's 9:45.
我猜另外170 人都迷路了
I guess the other 170 of you got lost,
那我们开始上课吧
so we'll just start.
有人选这门课
Now, some might say you guys are just taking this class
是因为觉得这门课简单， 或者把建筑学和
because it's easy or because you've confused architecture
考古学搞混了， 觉得我们要像
with archaeology and think we're gonna do
夺宝奇兵里那样 去玩些很酷的东西
some cool Indiana Jones stuff today.
但我认为...
But I think that...
我认为，也许你们之中 有一些人将来会成为建筑师
I think just maybe, we got some future architects in the house.
谁想成为一名建筑师的， 请举手～
Show of hands: who's thinking about a career in architecture?
Well,今天你们会改变的
Well, today, all that's gonna change.
跟我来
Follow me.
Hey. Uh,抱歉
Hey. Uh, sorry,
没有通行证的人 是不能入内的
nobody gets in here without a site pass.
没问题的，我是Ted Mosby, 这座大厦的建筑师
It's okay, I'm Ted Mosby, the architect of this building.
就算你是来大厦进行考古的
I don't care if you're the archaeologist of this building.
也不能入内
Site's closed.
下个景点！
Moving on!
那个早上Marshall的事务所
NARRATOR: That morning, Marshall's firm
正在准备 对 Gruber Pharmaceuticals
was getting the settlement offer
的索赔 Marshall 已经急不可待的
from Gruber Pharmaceuticals, and Marshall couldn't wait
想看到泰迪熊 变成一只伊渥克
to see the teddy bear turn into an Ewok.
Gruber Pharmaceuticals  将有毒废物倒入青蛙溪
Gruber Pharmaceuticals dumped toxic waste into Frog Creek,
而溪水汇入鳟鱼河 最后流入干净湖
a tributary of the Trout River that feeds into Clearwater Lake.
这三者现在都要新的名字了
All three of which now need new names.
现在是为地球母亲 赢得这场索赔的时候了
So it's time to win one for Mother Earth.
让我们干掉这些垃圾吧！
Let's take out the trash, shall we?!
- Yes! - 好，现在每个人带个袋子
- Yes! - All right, everyone grab a bag.
蓝色是可回收的 绿色的当化肥
Blue is recycling, green, compost.
我们走
There we go.
Sheila...
我们是来听你报价的
we're ready to hear your offer.
$24,000?
Yeah ,看起来很可观啊～
Yeah , that seems reasonable.
孩子们 我带着这25个学生在
NARRATOR: Kids, I was wandering the city
这城市里瞎逛 最后
with 25 Intro to Architecture students
只能让你们的Barney叔叔来 解救我
when your Uncle Barney came to my rescue.
OK,同学们，其实看一个建筑 怎么建造的没什么意思
Okay, guys, seeing a building get built, not that exciting.
真正有意思的是 看融资方面...
What's really exciting is the financial side of...
坐下，Ted, 我来
Sit down, Ted, I got this.
Hey, 那个络腮胡子 关灯
Hey, Weird Beard, lights!
大学时代... 一个充满疑惑的时代
College... it's a confusing time.
Oh, 不
Oh, no.
研究表明83%的大学生
Studies show that 83% of all college students
急切需要...
desperately need...
性教育！
sex lessons!
开灯!
Lights!
Barney,他们才18岁！
Barney, these are 18-year-olds!
Ted,已经18岁了！
Ted, these are 18-year-olds!
你有女朋友了
You have a girlfriend.
但她不喜欢伊渥克！
But she doesn't like Ewoks!
那又如何？
So what?
那又如何?! Bieber,关灯!
So what?! Bieber, lights!
在1983年, George Lucas 向世界展示了伊渥克
In 1983, George Lucas introduced the world to the Ewoks,
一种生活在Endor的 第二卫星的土著生物.
a race of creatures indigenous to the second moon of Endor.
现在要介绍伊渥克的 丰富的背景知识
Now, the Ewoks have a rich back-story
而电影没有向我们展示...
that the movie didn't really go into.
Barney,你还是直接跳到
Barney, why don't you just skip
跟Nora有关系的部分吧?
to the part about you and Nora?
好吧
(sighs) Fine.
Ah, 对了
Ah, yes.
最后,伊渥克把  星球大战影迷分成两类
Ultimately, Ewoks split Star Wars fandom into two camps:
一类出生于1973年五月25日之前，另一类出生于之后
those born before, and those born after May 25, 1973:
伊渥克之线
the Ewok Line.
所有出生于此线左边的观众
Anyone born on this side of the Ewok Line was
在星球大战出产时 都至少已经超过十岁
at least ten years old when Jedi came out,
他们已经太老了 无法体会到可爱的事物
and thus too old for something so cloying and cute.
出生于这边的人都喜欢 为什么呢？
Anyone born on this side loved the Ewoks because, why?
因为他们让你想起...
They reminded you of...
泰迪熊？
Our teddies?
他们让你想起泰迪熊！
They reminded you of your teddies.
谢谢，Gina.
Thank you, Gina.
你怎么知道她名字的？
How do you know her name?
所以，根据亘古不变的伊渥克之线法则
And so... by the immutable laws of the Ewok Line,
我的29岁的讨厌伊渥克的女友
my 29-year-old girlfriend who hates Ewoks
其实至少已经37岁了
must in fact be no younger than... 37.
只比Will的妈妈年轻了一岁
That's only a year younger than Will's mom.
你怎么知道我妈妈的？ 下课！
How do you know my mom? Class dismissed!
我要一个人待一会
I need to be alone.
好吧，我们继续
All right, we're moving on.
Ooh，我能来么？
Ooh, can I come?
Hey, 亲爱的
(cell phone rings) Hey, baby.
Hey,我只是想提醒你一下 我们跟Sonya医生约在了4点做体检
Hey, I just want to remind you we have Dr. Sonya at 4:00.
我会去的... 我只是感觉...我觉得非常沮丧
I'll be there. I'm sorry. I'm just... I'm bummed.
我们拿到和解协议了
We got our settlement offer today:
从一个日进斗金的公司 只拿到24000美元的索赔
$24,000 from a billion-dollar company.
Wow.我觉得 你们肯定不会很高兴
Wow. I take it people aren't happy about that.
我们赢了， 每个人都有香槟和蛋糕！
We won! Champagne and cake for everybody!
他们在 庆祝！
They're celebrating.
我觉得他们疯了！
I mean, it's crazy.
我们没资格 去吃蛋糕
We have no right to be eating cake.
你们有蛋糕？ 我马上到
There's cake?! I'm on my way!
与此同时 这场糟糕的实地教学还在继续
NARRATOR: Meanwhile, the worst field trip of all time was still trucking.
好了，这里这里让人心情澎湃
All right, this, this is exciting, okay?
就在这个房子里
This is the very room
我想到了GNB大厦 的创意
where I had the idea for the GNB Tower.
韦伯大字典把 "灵感"定义为...
Now, Webster's defines "inspiration" as...
Hold一下. 页面还在打开
Hold on. It's still loading.
Uh, hey，室友
Uh, hey, roomie.
Robin! Hey, 你在这里干嘛?
Robin! Hey, what are you doing here?
Well,我 正在  调整我的取向
Well, I was about to get my swerve on.
真的？
You were?
那么，你就是那个治疗师了？
So you're the therapist.
假装一个治疗师
You know, it's one thing to pretend to be a shrink
来勾搭女孩是一件事 这很正常
and bang your patients. That's normal.
但是，来真的， 哥们，这也太坑爹了
But to do it for real? A little creepy, bro.
Okay, 这一点也不坑爹
Okay, it's not creepy.
Ehhhh... 是有点坑爹
BOTH: Ehhhh... it's creepy.
同学们，举手表决：
Class, show of hands:
跟自己的心理治疗师约会 是不是很坑爹啊？
Who thinks it's creepy to date your therapist?
- 人民的选择 - 出去！
- Pollstered. - Get out!
好吧 我们继续！
All right. We're moving on!
同学们，在你们的左边
So, class, to your left,
你们会看到一些完美的建筑例子
you will see some excellent examples of
我们称之为：窗户
what we'd call windows.
我们现在要去哪里？
So where are we going now?
我没想法
I have no idea.
这简直就是个灾难
This is a disaster.
他们中有些人已经回家了
Some of them are already starting to go home.
而且好像有一家德国人 在跟着我们
Although we seem to have picked up a German family.
等等
BARNEY: Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
刚才Robin和她治疗师的事
That thing with Robin and her creepy therapist
让我有了好主意
gave me an idea.
Ted,我们对于过去的争论
Ted, we have here a way
有了一个前所未有的解决途径！
to solve every single debate we've ever had!
看看这样本：
I mean, just look at the sample:
男孩，女孩，黑人，亚洲人，还有德国人
guys, girls, blacks, Asians, a German family.
再也没有更好的机会了!
You can't pay for that kind of focus group!
通心粉色拉能算真正的色拉么？
Is macaroni salad really a salad?
认为不对的人，请举手！
Hands up if you say "no."
Ha!
Jacob还是Edward?
Jacob or Edward?
认为Edward的?
Who says Edward?
Ha, ha. See? 我早跟你说过了.
Ha, ha. See? I told you.
是Edward James Olmos.
It's Edward James Olmos.
你情愿跟一个死人
Would you rather have sex with a dead human being
还是跟一个活着的动... 哥们
or a live an...? Dude.
啥事? 注意底线
What? Find the line.
有谁觉得David Hasselhoff帅呆了?
Who thinks David Hasselhoff is awesome?
Hmm. 有道理
Hmm. It's true.
Okay.我有了， 如果你跟一个女孩子约会
Okay. I've got one. If you're dating a girl,
她对自己的年龄 撒谎了
and she lies about her age,
有谁同意 跟她分手的？
who says break up with her?
Yes, yes, 但假如她的撒谎对象
Yes, yes, but what if the person she's lying to
对年龄的偏见臭名昭著呢？
is notoriously shallow about age?
好吧，但是如果在 开始约会之前
Okay, but what if early in our relationship,
她对不要在两人之间
she made a really big deal
存在谎言做了承诺呢?
about wanting to not lie to each other?
假如她是个辣妹呢?
What if she's hot?
谁要五美元?
Who wants five bucks?
人民的选择!
Pollstered!
让我们开始吧！
Let's do this.
(giggling)
(clears throat)
Hmm? Yeah.
(murmurs) Hmm? Yeah.
Mm...
(giggling)
Okay, 真是坑爹啊
Mm...
这简直比日和漫画还坑爹
Okay, this is creepy.
你是我的病人
It's Crispin Glover creepy.
你跟我说了你的私人秘密
You were my patient.
这简直跟你的妇科医生约会一样
You shared intimate stuff.
It would be like dating your gynecologist.
你很脆弱
You were vulnerable.
我们不能对过去 避而不谈
That's not something we can move past.
是不能
(sighs) Guess not.
那么跟你的妇科医生也感觉很差么？
So, dating your gyno, that's bad, too?
Oh, Robin.
开玩笑啦！
Kidding!
我们又有新的蛋糕啦！
Look, we've got another one!
(laughing)
来吧，来咬一口！
Come on, have a bite.
不，这个事关原则！
No, it's a matter of principle.
我不管这个蛋糕有多好吃
I don't care how good it is,
我不会再吃第三块蛋糕了！
I'm not gonna have a third piece of cake!
Okay, 同事们，我们今天过的很开心
Okay, guys, you all had a lot of fun today,
现在让我们... 过的更开心！
but now it's time... to have even more fun!
又是一个蛋糕!
Another cake!
又是一个蛋糕?!
MARSHALL: Another cake?!
你们究竟怎么了?!
What is the matter with you people?!
今天的和解协议就像一坨熊熊燃烧的...
That settlement today was a flaming pile of...
小狗...
puppies...
还没着火的那种！
that aren't on fire!
看看外面环境正在遭受着怎样的破坏,
Look at what's happening to the environment,
而我们却在这里载歌载舞?
and we're here doing the limbo?
我们应该为我们自己感到羞耻
I mean, we should be ashamed of ourselves!
先生，我的意思是...
Sir, all I meant was...
从现在起十年之内
Ten years from right now,
所有在外面的人都会死掉！
everyone outside in that bullpen will be dead.
神马?
What?
我看过最新的报告了,  Marsh.
I've seen the latest research, Marsh.
你知道我总是在说
You know how I'm always saying
现在拯救地球还不算太迟?
it's not too late to save the planet?
现在拯救地球 已经太迟了！
It's too late to save the planet.
现在我们什么都不能做
There's nothing to do but sit back
只能干坐等死
and await our inevitable doom.
噢，天哪，真是太可爱了
(noisemaker tooting)
Oh, my goodness, a pi?ata!
再给我一分钟，Larry.
Just give me one minute, Larry.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们可怕的，难以避免的灭亡!
Our grotesque, inevitable doom!
当然，你不能 现在出去
Now, of course, you can't go around
告诉所有人
telling all the people
这艘 环保主义的大船
that the good ship Environmentalism
正在驶向落日
has sailed off into the sunset.
这样会引起恐慌
There would cause a panic.
或者，我们能做的是
So, instead, what we do is,
我们去工作， 摆着一张笑脸
we come to work, we put on a happy face,
我们起诉那些大公司
and we sue the big guys
让他们赔偿一些钱 正好用来买蛋糕
for just enough money for some cake
而这之后未过滤的射线 将像晒咸鱼那样的晒干我们
before the unfiltered rays of the sun fry us like chalupas,
我们的肺里 将会填满海水
and our lungs fill up with salt water,
然后我们都死了
and we all die!
Mmm.这蛋糕太好吃了，世界太美好了！
Mmm. This cake is delicious. Everything's fine.
Ugh, 今天糟透了！
Ugh, this day sucks.
Kevin和我分手了
Kevin and I are kaputski.
你觉得这样就糟糕么?
You think that's bad?
这个世界就要毁灭了
The world is coming to an end.
你觉得这样就糟糕么?
You think that's bad?
我女朋友37岁了!
My girlfriend is 37!
我的现场教学 跟想象的差距太大了
And my field trip is not going as well as I'd hoped.
Hmm.
今天糟透了
This day sucks.
Mosby教授, 今天的课结束了么？
Professor Mosby, is the field trip over?
我们想回家了
We'd like to go home.
Yeah, 下课了
Yeah, it's over.
再见（德语）
Auf wiedersehen.
我只是想激励他们,
I just wanted to inspire them,
就像我的老师激励我一样
you know, like my professors inspired me.
但是，到了一天结束
But here we are, at the end of the day...
Hey,同学们，即兴测试，
Hey, class, quick question.
Uh, 有没有人想成为一个建筑师的?
Uh, is anyone here thinking of becoming an architect?
(clucks tongue)
Really?
Yeah, 哥们. 说真的,
Yeah, dude. I mean,
所有工作都烂透了
all jobs suck,
但在下午四点
but it's 4:00 in the afternoon,
你跟你的朋友在酒吧
and you're out at a bar with your friends,
所以看起来似乎也不是太差
so the hours can't be that bad.
所以...
So...
yeah, 我不知道，我会考虑一下的
yeah, I don't know, I'd think about it.
你把我感动了 Oh!
(voice cracking): I got through to you. Oh!
我是说，假如当一名DJ不成功的话
I mean, that is, if becoming a deejay doesn't pan out.
你会成为一名伟大的建筑师的
You are gonna be a great architect.
他成了一名DJ
NARRATOR: He became a deejay.
Robin, 你怎么在这里?
Robin, what are you doing here?
我跟你说过了，我不能当你的心理治疗师
I told you I can't be your therapist.
我知道
I know.
今天我是你的心理治疗师
Today, I am your therapist.
神马?
What?
你自己说过了
You said yourself,
我总是给自己找不开心的理由
I'm always looking for reasons not to be happy.
现在我要试图改变
Well, I'm trying to change that.
所以我们不能在一起 仅仅是因为
So, if the only reason we can't be together
我对你打开心扉而变得脆弱的话
is because I was in a vulnerable place
在接下来的两个小时里 我们会相互了解
for the first two hours we knew each other
这两小时是你欠我的
then that is two hours of vulnerability you owe me.
坐下
Sit down.
Okay.
Okay,但是我必须要提醒你，作为一个专业人士我很有抵抗力...
Okay, but I must warn you, as a professional, I'm immune to...
跟我谈谈你的母亲吧
Tell me about your mother.
她简直就是一个控制狂!
Everything she says is a manipulation!
在我七岁的时候...
When I was seven years old...
Mr. Cootes.
- Hey. - 对于你昨天说的
- Hey. - Listen, I've been thinking
我想了很久
a lot about what you said yesterday,
我们都会死
about how we're all gonna die.
Oh,我不会死
Oh, I'm not gonna die.
我在科来拉多买了一个废弃矿井
I bought an old mine shaft in Colorado.
我花了六个月 去贮藏罐装食物
I've spent the last six months filling it with canned goods,
还有来复枪 去PT下载了五季的 胜利之光
assault rifles and all five seasons of Friday Night Lights.
Okay,首先，你可以跳过第二季
Okay, first of all, you can skip season two.
第二，在我们谈话之后...
Second of all, after our talk...
我原本打算 放纵自己的生活
I came pretty close to giving up myself.
但是当我跟我的妻子 去医生那边
But then I went to the doctor with my wife...
做检查的时候...
and...
我看到了这个.
(taps key)
I saw this.
男孩女孩?
Boy or girl?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是我知道，我现在不能放弃.
But I know I sure as hell can't give up now.
所以，假如你们是想找一个
So, if you're just looking for someone
给跳竹排舞拉杆子的人
to hold the other end of the limbo stick,
你们找错人了 知道为什么么？
you got the wrong guy for the job, and you know why?
因为你比这办公室 里的人都高么？
'Cause you're three feet taller than everyone in this office?
不，因为，假如我在这里工作
No. Because if I am gonna work here,
明天早上的第一件事
then first thing tomorrow morning,
就是走进Gruber Pharmaceuticals,
I'm walking down to Gruber Pharmaceuticals,
退回他们的赔偿
and I'm rejecting their offer.
虽千万人， 吾往矣
Even if I have to do it myself.
(door opens)
听着，我想你知道...我知道了
Listen, I want you to know... I know.
知道什么?
Know what?
Nora.
Barney.
想说什么就快说
Just say what you're gonna say!
我知道你很老！
I know you're old!
我内心有过挣扎
And I've been struggling with it,
但当我看到你的时候
but when I look at you...
我不在乎 因为我真很喜欢你
I don't care, because I really like you.
即使你已经37, 你身材还是很好!
And because for 37, you are keeping it toit!
你觉得我37?
You think I'm 37?
Well, 假如你真的29,
Well, if you were really 29,
你在看到伊渥克的时候
then you would have been a little kid
应该还是个小孩 而你会爱上他们
the first time you saw the Ewoks and you would have loved them.
Barney, 我在去年之前
Barney, I didn't see any of the Star Wars
没看过一集的星球大战
movies until last year.
你...你是29!
You... you're 29!
你还有一年的黄金年龄！
You still have one good year left.
- 神马? - 没神马.
- What? - Nothing.
Mm...
Naveen是神经外科医生,
But Naveen's the neurosurgeon,
理所当然 他应该精神集中!
so of course he gets all the attention!
Oh, Naveen很聪明
Oh, Naveen is so smart,
他给人的大脑做手术!
he operates on people's brains!
Well,猜猜怎么着，妈妈?!
Well, guess what, Mom?!
我治疗人的意识！
I treat the human mind!
时间到
Our time is up.
我觉得这么做不行
(exhales)
I don't think this is gonna work.
我把你吓到了？
I scared you off, didn't I?
不，我的意思是说 不能当你的心理治疗师
No, I mean, I don't think I can be your therapist.
你太可爱了
You're really cute.
第二天
NARRATOR: The next day,
Marshall一个人回到了 Gruber Pharmaceuticals
Marshall returned to Gruber Pharmaceuticals alone.
既然你们承认了污染了湖水
I mean, you admit that you polluted the lake.
我们有证据
We got the evidence.
我们有图表
We got the charts.
和鱼...
The fish...
鱼, huh?
Fish, huh?
鱼很奇怪
Fish are weird.
你们有没有想过鱼的名字？
You ever think about the names of fish?
想想看！
I mean, come on.
鲤鱼
Carp.
Garrison,真是个可喜的意外啊
Garrison, what a nice surprise.
你的明星见习生...
Your star apprentice was just, uh...
"跟比目鱼一样."
"Floundering."
一点点,关于鱼
Little, little fish humor
的冷笑话
for you guys.
情况很不好
It was not going well.
我是来拒绝你们的24,000的
I'm here to turn down the 24,000.
Well, 也许我们能给你 24,500.
Well, I can maybe get you 24,500.
不...够...多
Not... good... enough.
我们要怎么办？
Where are we going?
战争，孩子
To war, son.
我们要去赴战！
We're going to war.
我们要拯救这个星球
We're going to save the planet.
孩子，现在我们知道 他们做到了
NARRATOR: And kids, as we now know, they did.
Hey,你知道昨晚放什么了?
Hey, you know what was on last night?
- 为人师表 - Mm.
- Stand and Deliver. - Mm.
- 太棒了 - Mm-hmm.
- So good. - Mm-hmm.
Jacob James Olmos怎么样了?
Whatever happened to Jacob James Olmos?
谁?
Who?
Jacob James Olmos. 这哥们后来怎么了?
Jacob James Olmos. Whatever happened to that guy?
他不存在
He never existed.
是Edward James Olmos.
It's Edward James Olmos.
你疾呼对了
You're Olmos correct.
是Jacob James Olmos.
It's Jacob James Olmos.
- 是Edward James Olmos. - Jacob James Olmos.
- It's Edward James Olmos. - Jacob James Olmos.
Edward James Olmos.
- 你在开玩笑吧....? - 你是认真的...?
- You're joking, right...? - Are you serious...?
- 认真的. - Jacob James Olmos.
- Seriously. - Jacob James Olmos.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==